<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <place>
        <id>1</id>
        <name>Auckland</name>
        <category>1</category>
        <description>Auckland, in the North Island of New Zealand, is the largest and most populous
            urban area in the country. Auckland has a population of 1,413,700, which constitutes 31
			percent of the country's population.
            It is part of the wider Auckland Region, which includes the rural areas and towns north
            and south of the urban area, plus the islands of the Hauraki Gulf, resulting in a total
            population of 1,527,100 that is governed by the Auckland Council. Auckland also has the
            largest Polynesian population of any city in the world. In Māori, Auckland's name is
            Tāmaki Makaurau and the transliterated version of Auckland is Ākarana.
            Auckland straddles the Auckland volcanic field, which has produced about 90 volcanic
            eruptions from 50 volcanoes in the last 90,000 years. It is the only city in the world
            built on a basaltic volcanic field that is still active. It is estimated that the field
            will stay active for about 1 million years. Surface features include cones, lakes,
            lagoons, islands and depressions, and several have produced extensive lava flows. Some
            of the cones and flows have been partly or completely quarried away.
            Auckland lies on and around an isthmus, less than two kilometres wide at its narrowest
            point, between Mangere Inlet and the Tamaki River. There are two harbours in the
            Auckland urban area surrounding this isthmus: Waitemata Harbour to the north, which
            opens east to the Hauraki Gulf, and Manukau Harbour to the south, which opens west to
            the Tasman Sea. The total coastline of Auckland is 3,702 km in length.
            Bridges span parts of both harbours, notably the Auckland Harbour Bridge crossing the
            Waitemata Harbour west of the Auckland Central Business District (CBD). The Mangere
            Bridge and the Upper Harbour Bridge span the upper reaches of the Manukau and Waitemata
            Harbours, respectively. In earlier times, portage paths crossed the narrowest sections
            of the isthmus</description>
        <picture>auckland_pic</picture>
        <latitude>-36.84846</latitude>
        <longitude>174.76333</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>

    <place>
        <id>2</id>
        <name>Mission Bay</name>
        <category>2</category>
        <description>Mission Bay  is a seaside suburb of Auckland city. The suburb's beach is a
            popular resort, located alongside Tamaki Drive. The area also has a wide range of
            eateries. Mission Bay is located seven kilometres to the east of the city centre, on
            the southern shore of the Waitematā Harbour, between Orākei and Kohimarama. It covers
            an area of 1.08 km2 (267 acres), about three quarters of which comprises low hills,
            surrounding the remaining quarter, which slopes down to the sea. Local government of
            Mission Bay is the responsibility of the Orakei Local Board, which also includes the
            suburbs of Orākei, Kohimarama, St Heliers, Glendowie, St Johns, Meadowbank, Remuera
            and Ellerslie.
            Mission Bay sits on three parcels of land comprising part of the Kohimarama block
            bought from the Crown in the early 1840s. The area used to be referred to as ‘Kohimarama’,
            a name now given to a neighbouring suburb Kohimarama.</description>
        <picture>mission_bay</picture>
        <latitude>-36.84825</latitude>
        <longitude>174.83177</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>

    <place>
        <id>3</id>
        <name>Point Chevalier</name>
        <category>2</category>
        <description>Point Chevalier Beach is a suburb and peninsula in the west of the city of
            Auckland in the north of New Zealand. It is located five kilometres to the west of
            the city centre on the southern shore of the Waitemata Harbour.
            Point Chevalier Beach is one of the best beaches on the Waitemata Harbour, and certainly
            the best west of the city. With its safe swimming, ample shade and the excellent
            playground in adjacent Colye Park, it makes a great inner city outing for the family.
            Coyle Park is at the northern end of Point Chevalier Rd, where there is ample parking.
            The park has an excellent and newly revamped playground and acres of space for the kids
            to run around. The park is at the very tip of the peninsula so there are good views out
            over the harbour.</description>
        <picture>point_chev</picture>
        <latitude>-36.85491</latitude>
        <longitude>174.70201</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>

    <place>
        <id>4</id>
        <name>Cheltenham beach</name>
        <category>2</category>
        <description>Relax and breathe in the fresh sea air as you explore Devonport’s famous
            Cheltenham beach. Marvel at the awesome sea views from the shore or take a refreshing
            dip in the calm ocean waters.
            The long sandy stretch of Cheltenham Beach is popular with locals and visitors for
            swimming, strolling and relaxing! There are also grassy areas that are great for picnics
            and enjoying fish and chips by the beach.
            Located 1.5 km away from the ferry terminal – it’s an easy and scenic walk to Cheltenham
            Beach. Along the route you will see beautifully restored Victorian villas – many with
            spectacular ocean views.
            North Head can be easily accessed from Cheltenham Beach and the Vauxhall Road shops are
            also conveniently located nearby.</description>
        <picture>cheltenham</picture>
        <latitude>-36.82165</latitude>
        <longitude>174.80915</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>

    <place>
        <id>5</id>
        <name>Orewa beach</name>
        <category>2</category>
        <description>Orewa, a town in New Zealand's North Island, lies on the Hibiscus Coast, just
            north of the base of the Whangaparaoa Peninsula and 40 kilometres north of central
            Auckland.
            Orewa beach is one of the longest and safest beaches in Auckland. One of the more
            notable events on the beach is the Orewa Big Dig. This is an annual event organized
            by the local Lions Club, where children dig in the sand to find prizes. All monies
            raised go to local community groups. Orewa Community Centre is located in Orewa Square.
            The Hibiscus Community Centre is located at 214E Hibiscus Coast Highway.</description>
        <picture>orewa</picture>
        <latitude>-36.58448</latitude>
        <longitude>174.69645</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>

    <place>
        <id>6</id>
        <name>Farmers Santa Parade</name>
        <category>3</category>
        <description>The Auckland Santa Parade features all the amazing pageantry, fun and surprises
            that have made this annual Auckland City extravaganza a perennial favourite.
            November.</description>
        <picture>santaparade</picture>
        <latitude>-36.84846</latitude>
        <longitude>174.76333</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>

    <place>
        <id>7</id>
        <name>New Zealand Fashion Week</name>
        <category>3</category>
        <description>Held over seven days, New Zealand Fashion week presents a number of fashion
            shows for well known and up and coming New Zealand designers.
            September</description>
        <picture>fas_week</picture>
        <latitude>-36.84846</latitude>
        <longitude>174.76333</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>

    <place>
        <id>8</id>
        <name>Auckland Lantern Festival</name>
        <category>3</category>
        <description>Be enchanted - immerse yourself in the magic of the Auckland Lantern Festival
            in two stunning venues, each showcasing the diversity of Chinese culture.
            February</description>
        <picture>lanternfest</picture>
        <latitude>-36.84846</latitude>
        <longitude>174.76333</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>

    <place>
        <id>9</id>
        <name>Auckland Arts Festival</name>
        <category>3</category>
        <description>The globally-recognised Auckland Arts Festival celebrates people and culture,
            and showcases the cultural diversity and vibrant energy of New Zealand's largest city.
            March</description>
        <picture>artfest</picture>
        <latitude>-36.84846</latitude>
        <longitude>174.76333</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>

    <place>
        <id>10</id>
        <name>Restaurant Month</name>
        <category>3</category>
        <description>Indulge in some of Auckland’s best cuisine during Restaurant Month. Try
            specially created menus at more than 100 central city restaurants, watch live chef
            demonstrations, enjoy tastings and talks at the Wine AKL event, and don’t miss the
            delicious international street food at Street Eats.
            August</description>
        <picture>rest_month</picture>
        <latitude>-36.84846</latitude>
        <longitude>174.76333</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>

    <place>
        <id>11</id>
        <name>Auckland War Memorial Museum</name>
        <category>4</category>
        <description>Auckland War Memorial Museum is one of New Zealand's most important museums
            and war memorials. Its collections concentrate on New Zealand history (and especially
            the history of the Auckland Region), natural history, as well as military history.
            The museum is also one of the most iconic Auckland buildings, constructed in the
            neo-classicist style, and sitting on a grassed plinth (the remains of a dormant volcano)
            in the Auckland Domain, a large public park close to the Auckland CBD.</description>
        <picture>war_museum</picture>
        <latitude>-36.86038</latitude>
        <longitude>174.77782</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>

    <place>
        <id>12</id>
        <name>New Zealand Maritime Museum</name>
        <category>4</category>
        <description>The New Zealand Maritime Museum is New Zealand's premier maritime museum. It is
            located on Hobson Wharf Auckland, adjacent to Viaduct Harbour. It houses exhibitions
            spanning New Zealands maritime history from the first Polynesian explorers to modern day
            triumphs at the America's Cup.
            Its Maori name is 'Te Huiteanaui-A-Tangaroa' - holder of the treasures of Tangaroa
            (the Sea God).</description>
        <picture>maritime</picture>
        <latitude>-36.84213</latitude>
        <longitude>174.76348</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>

    <place>
        <id>13</id>
        <name>Auckland Art Gallery Toi o Tāmaki</name>
        <category>4</category>
        <description>Auckland Art Gallery Toi o Tāmaki is the principal public gallery in Auckland,
            New Zealand, and has the most extensive collection of national and international art in
            New Zealand. It frequently hosts travelling international exhibitions.
            Set below the hilltop Albert Park in the central-city area of Auckland, the gallery was
            established in 1888 as the first permanent art gallery in New Zealand.
            The building originally housed the Auckland Art Gallery as well as the Auckland public
            library opening with collections donated by benefactors Governor Sir George Grey and
            James Tannock Mackelvie.</description>
        <picture>art_galery</picture>
        <latitude>-36.85136</latitude>
        <longitude>174.76624</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>

    <place>
        <id>14</id>
        <name>Papakura Museum</name>
        <category>4</category>
        <description>Continue to look at the past and draw on that knowledge as you journey forward
            to the future.
            Papakura Museum is a community museum founded by members of the Papakura and Districts
            Historical Society (PDHS) and which continues to function with the aid of Society
            volunteers. It is home to a continually growing collection of photographs, objects and
            documents which tell the story of Papakura and surrounding Districts.</description>
        <picture>papakura_museum</picture>
        <latitude>-37.06384</latitude>
        <longitude>174.94158</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>

    <place>
        <id>15</id>
        <name>Albert Park</name>
        <category>5</category>
        <description>Albert Park is a public park in central Auckland, bounded by Wellesley Street
            East, Princes Street, Bowen Avenue and Kitchener Street. From the entrance at the corner
            of Bowen Ave and Kitchener St, sealed footpaths climb steeply through native trees to
            the large flat area at the summit, where a formal layout of paths and flower gardens
            encircle a fountain.</description>
        <picture>albert_park</picture>
        <latitude>-36.85045</latitude>
        <longitude>174.76766</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>

    <place>
        <id>16</id>
        <name>Cornwall Park</name>
        <category>5</category>
        <description>Cornwall Park is the legacy of Sir John Logan Campbell. Originally
        the land was a farm owned by him on the outskirts of Auckland. Upon his return from Italy
        in the 1880s he intended to build a great family residence on the slopes of the hill (where
        the current tearooms are) and planted many trees including olives on the slopes. Eventually
        he constructed a house closer to town (the land is now part of the Parnell Rose gardens).
        By about 1900 he realised that Auckland's suburbs were spreading at an alarming rate and he
        decided to leave the Greenlane property to the city as a park. Parts of the park, about 120
        hectares (296.5 acres), are still run as a farm today, providing Aucklanders with access to
        an example of rural life in the heart of the city.
        One Tree Hill Domain (118 acres / 48 hectares) is an Auckland Council-administered park
        adjoining Cornwall Park (425 acres / 172 hectares) creating a total of 220 hectares (540
        acres) of public green space.</description>
        <picture>cornwall</picture>
        <latitude>-36.89779</latitude>
        <longitude>174.78769</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>

    <place>
        <id>17</id>
        <name>The Auckland Domain</name>
        <category>5</category>
        <description>The Auckland Domain is Auckland's oldest park, and at 75 hectares one
        of the largest in the city. Located in the central suburb of Grafton, the park contains all
        of the explosion crater and most of the surrounding tuff ring of the Pukekawa volcano.
        The Auckland Domain volcano, Pukekawa, is one of the oldest in the Auckland Volcanic Field,
        and consists of a large explosion crater surrounded by a tuff ring with a small scoria cone
        (Pukekaroro) in the centre of the crater. Its tuff ring, created by many explosive eruptions,
        is made of a mixture of volcanic ash, lapilli and fragmented sandstone country rock.</description>
        <picture>domain</picture>
        <latitude>-36.85893</latitude>
        <longitude>174.77549</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>

    <place>
        <id>18</id>
        <name>Western Springs</name>
        <category>5</category>
        <description>Western Springs is a residential suburb and park in the west of the city of
            Auckland in the north of New Zealand. It is located four kilometres to the west of the
            city centre. The park is situated to the north of State Highway 16 and the residential
            suburb is located southeast of the park on the opposite side of State Highway 16.
            The suburb is dominated by the large park (featuring a lake with a variety of birdlife),
            within which are situated Auckland Zoo, Western Springs Stadium and M.O.T.A.T.
            (the Museum of Transport and Technology). The park is the location of the annual
            Pasifika Festival, one of Auckland's most popular public events.
            Western Springs Park consists of a sanctuary for wildlife, surrounding a lake fed by the
            natural springs. There are walking paths surrounding the lake with bridges going across
            sections of it. Auckland Zoo, MOTAT and Western Springs Stadium are all situated around
            the park.</description>
        <picture>westernsprings</picture>
        <latitude>-36.86816</latitude>
        <longitude>174.72590</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>

    <place>
        <id>19</id>
        <name>Long Bay Regional Park</name>
        <category>5</category>
        <description>Long Bay Beach provides 1 km of white sand, safe swimming as well as a
            tree-lined park environment which makes it a popular family attraction. The sea off
            Long Bay is in the Long Bay-Okura Marine Reserve. Multiple park areas on the verge of
            the beach provide: playgrounds with equipment suitable for preschoolers and older
            children; flying fox; miniature ride-on train; restaurant; picnic and BBQ areas
            (which can also be booked for private functions via the Auckland Council) and walking
            tracks. The park and beach are monitored by park rangers who enforce park rules
            including dog exclusion areas, no fishing and no littering.
            Maori occupants of Long Bay gave it the name Oneroa, meaning long expanse of sand. Ngati
            Kahu was the main tribal group to live here until European settlement began in the
            1850s.</description>
        <picture>long_bay</picture>
        <latitude>-36.67574</latitude>
        <longitude>174.74592</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>

    <place>
        <id>20</id>
        <name>Shakespear Regional Park</name>
        <category>5</category>
        <description>Shakespear Regional Park is a nature park in the Auckland Region of New Zealand.
            It is located at the tip of the Whangaparaoa Peninsula, and is named after the
            Shakespear family which bought the land in the 1880s from local Maori.
            The Park is home to three walkways, Heritage Trail, Lookout Track and Tiri Tiri Track.
            Much of the coastline is lined by sandstone cliffs, which shelter the beach-lined Te
            Haruhi Bay. At the Park's western border, a narrow lowland separates Okoromai and Army
            Bays.
            Together with New Zealand Defence Force land to the north, most of the Park lies within
            the Shakespear Open Sanctuary. A 1.7-kilometre (1.1 mi) pest/predator-proof fence
            (completed March 2011) across the peninsula between protects the park's wildlife. This
            includes resident invertebrates and lizards, along with birds migrating from the nearby
            Tiritiri Matangi island sanctuary. Brodifacoum poison airdrops were conducted in July
            2011 to eradicate mammalian pests. The Shakespear Open Sanctuary Society has worked with
            the government landowners to establish and develop the sanctuary.</description>
        <picture>shekspeare</picture>
        <latitude>-36.60780</latitude>
        <longitude>174.82290</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>

    <place>
        <id>21</id>
        <name>Crater Hill</name>
        <category>6</category>
        <description>Crater Hill is one of the volcanoes of the Auckland Volcanic Field. It consists
            of an explosion crater about 600m wide, partly filled with water.
            Late in the eruption sequence lava welled up inside the explosion crater creating a lava
            lake. This lake began cooling on the surface and around the edge, creating a solid
            basalt crust. When the molten lava withdrew back down the volcano's throat, the crust
            surface collapsed, creating the island in the middle of the present lake, and some of
            the solid basalt was left around the inside walls of the crater marking the former level
            of the lava lake. Two lava caves – Selfs and Underground Press Lava Caves – exist
            beneath the remnant crust on the south side of the crater.</description>
        <picture>craterhill</picture>
        <latitude>-36.98644</latitude>
        <longitude>174.82674</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>

    <place>
        <id>22</id>
        <name>Greenmount</name>
        <category>6</category>
        <description>Green Hill (also Matanginui or Greenmount) is one of the volcanoes in the
            Auckland volcanic field, located in the suburb of Greenmount. Its scoria cone had a peak
            78 metres above sea level (around 48 m higher than the surrounding land), and had a
            grove of karaka trees. The hill was the site of a pā. It was quarried from 1870 onwards,
            and has been mostly quarried away. The site is now Greenmount landfill. Green Hill and
            nearby Otara Hill were together referred to as Bessy Bell and Mary Gray after an old
            Scottish ballad.</description>
        <picture>greenhill</picture>
        <latitude>-36.93840</latitude>
        <longitude>174.89788</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>

    <place>
        <id>23</id>
        <name>Hampton Park</name>
        <category>6</category>
        <description>Hampton Park is one of the volcanoes in the Auckland Volcanic Field. A small
            scoria cone reaching 35 m above sea level, with a shallow crater around 50 m wide, which
            has been modified by quarrying. The scoria cone sits in the centre of a much larger
            explosion crater - the eastern arc of the surrounding tuff ring is still present.
            Stone from the volcano was used to build dry-stone walls and the nearby St John's Church
            built on the tuff ring crest.This volcanoes is a cone volcano.</description>
        <picture>hampton_park</picture>
        <latitude>-36.95100</latitude>
        <longitude>174.89552</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>

    <place>
        <id>24</id>
        <name>Lake Pupuke</name>
        <category>6</category>
        <description>Lake Pupuke is a heart-shaped freshwater lake occupying a volcanic explosion
            crater between the suburbs of Takapuna and Milford on the North Shore of Auckland, New
            Zealand.
            Separated from the sea by less than 200 m at one point, it has a circumference of about
            4.5 km and reaches 57m in depth. It is popular for recreational activities and the
            lakefront property around it.
            The crater wall has been quarried in several places, most intensely on the western side
            between Shea Terrace and Rangitira Avenue, where Smales Quarry continues to operate.
            A long thin lagoon called Quarry Lake has been formed there by flooding a former quarry
            area.</description>
        <picture>lake_pupuke</picture>
        <latitude>-36.78016</latitude>
        <longitude>174.76611</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>

    <place>
        <id>25</id>
        <name>Mount Eden</name>
        <category>6</category>
        <description>Mt Eden (Maungawhau) is one of the most prominent volcanic cones remaining in
            the Auckland region. Erupting about 15,000 years ago from three overlapping scoria
            cones, it formed a huge scoria mound with a central crater from the last eruption.
            Lava flowed out from the base of the mound, and in some places the lava is more than
            60 metres thick.
            Maungawhau was a significant fortified pā, large enough to provide refuge for several
            hundred people. Extensive earthworks modified the steep upper slopes of the
            cone.</description>
        <picture>mteden</picture>
        <latitude>-36.87714</latitude>
        <longitude>174.76426</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>

    <place>
        <id>26</id>
        <name>One Tree Hill</name>
        <category>6</category>
        <description>One Tree Hil is a 182-metre (597 ft) volcanic peak in Auckland, New Zealand.
            It is an important memorial place for both Maori and other New Zealanders. The suburb
            around the base of the hill is also called One Tree Hill; it is surrounded by the
            suburbs of Royal Oak to the west, and clockwise, Epsom, Greenlane, Oranga, and Onehunga.
            The summit provides views across the Auckland area, and allows visitors to see both of
            Auckland's harbours.
            The hill's scoria cones were erupted from three craters – one is intact and two have
            been breached by lava flows that rafted away part of the side of the scoria cone. Lava
            flows went in all directions, many towards Onehunga, covering an area of 20km2, making
            it the second largest  of the Auckland volcanic field, behind Rangitoto Island. The age
            of eruption is currently unknown, but it is older than 28,500 years as it has a mantling
            of volcanic ash erupted at that time from Te Tatua-a-Riukiuta volcano.
            When Auckland was founded as a colonial town a tree stood near the summit which gave the
            hill its English name.</description>
        <picture>onetreehill</picture>
        <latitude>-36.90003</latitude>
        <longitude>174.78320</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>

    <place>
        <id>27</id>
        <name>Rangitoto Island</name>
        <category>6</category>
        <description>Rangitoto Island is a volcanic island in the Hauraki Gulf near Auckland, New
            Zealand. The 5.5 km wide island is an iconic and widely visible landmark of Auckland
            with its distinctive symmetrical shield volcano cone rising 260 metres (850 ft) high
            over the Hauraki Gulf. Rangitoto is the most recent and the largest (2311 hectares) of
            the approximately 50 volcanoes of the Auckland volcanic field.
            Rangitoto was formed by a series of eruptions between 550 and 600 years ago. The
            eruptions occurred in two episodes, 10–50 yrs apart, and are thought to have lasted for
            several years during the later shield-forming episode. The first episode erupted most
            of the volcanic ash that mantles Motutapu Island next door, and produced the lower,
            northern, scoria cone. </description>
        <picture>rangitoto</picture>
        <latitude>-36.78988</latitude>
        <longitude>174.86722</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>
	
	<place>
        <id>28</id>
        <name>Little Rangitoto</name>
        <category>6</category>
        <description>Little Rangitoto (also Maungarahiri) is one of the volcanoes in the Auckland 
		Volcanic Field. This scoria cone had a peak 75 m above sea level (30 m higher than the 
		surrounding land) before it was mostly quarried away. The quarry site is now Little Rangitoto 
		Reserve, having been partly filled with refuse in the 1950s. Remnants of the southern slopes 
		of the cone lie south of the reserve and underlie houses in Ventnor Rd. A lava flow burst 
		forth from the northwestern base of the cone and flowed north down the valley west of Orakei 
		Basin tuff ring and out into what is now Hobson Bay.</description>
        <picture>little_rangitoto</picture>
        <latitude>-36.87562</latitude>
        <longitude>174.80954</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>
	
	<place>
        <id>29</id>
        <name>Mangere Lagoon</name>
        <category>6</category>
        <description>Mangere Lagoon is a lagoon in the Manukau Harbour, New Zealand. 
		It occupies a volcanic crater or maar which is part of the Auckland volcanic field. 
		Oval and about 600m long, it has a small restored scoria island remaining in the centre.
		In the 1930s efforts were made to drain the swamp for conversion to pasture, while in the late 1950s, 
		earthworks for sewage sludge ponds in the lagoon removed the scoria cone and the crater was divided into ponds.</description>
        <picture>mangere</picture>
        <latitude>-36.95635</latitude>
        <longitude>174.77755</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>
	
	<place>
        <id>30</id>
        <name>Mangere Mountain</name>
        <category>6</category>
        <description>Mangere Mountain in Mangere Domain is one of the largest volcanic cones in the 
		Auckland volcanic field, with a peak 106 metres above sea level. It was the site of a major 
		pā (Māori fortified settlement) and many of the pā's earthworks are still obvious. 
		It offers spectacular panoramic views of Auckland from its location in the suburb of Mangere.
		The volcano features two large craters. It has a wide crater with a lava dome near its centre, 
		a feature shared by no other volcano in Auckland. It last erupted approximately 18,000 years ago.</description>
        <picture>mangere_mountain</picture>
        <latitude>-36.94989</latitude>
        <longitude>174.78290</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>
	
	<place>
        <id>31</id>
        <name>Matukutureia</name>
        <category>6</category>
        <description>Matukutūreia (also McLaughlins Mountain) is one of the volcanic cones in the Auckland Volcanic Field. 
		It has a peak 73 metres above sea level, and was the site of a pā. The scoria cone was originally crescent-shaped 
		and featured Māori terraces and kumara pits, before extensive quarrying reduced it to a pyramid-shaped mound big 
		enough to support the summit water tank for Papatoetoe. A small part of the summit and the eastern side of the 
		cone were left unquarried, plus a large area of lava flows to the south of the cone remains intact. These 
		remaining parts have recently been transferred to Department of Conservation Management, primarily because 
		of the high heritage values of the Matukuturua Stonefields gardens.</description>
        <picture>matukutureia</picture>
        <latitude>-37.01575</latitude>
        <longitude>174.84285</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>
	
	<place>
        <id>32</id>
        <name>Browns Island</name>
        <category>6</category>
        <description>Browns Island or Motukorea is a small New Zealand island, in the Hauraki Gulf north of Musick Point,
		one of the best preserved volcanoes in the Auckland Volcanic Field. The age of eruption is currently unknown. 
		Due to centuries of cultivation, little native bush remains except on the north-eastern cliffs, leaving the 
		volcanic landforms easily visible. It exhibits the landforms from three styles of eruption. The island consists 
		of one main scoria cone with a deep crater, a small remnant arc of the tuff ring forming the cliffs in the northeast, 
		and the upper portions of lava flows. The area was dry land when the eruptions occurred, but much of the lava is now 
		submerged beneath the sea.</description>
        <picture>browns_island</picture>
        <latitude>-36.83021</latitude>
        <longitude>174.89453</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>
	
	<place>
        <id>33</id>
        <name>Mount Hobson</name>
        <category>6</category>
        <description>Mount Hobson (also known as Ōhinerangi and Remuwera) is a 143 m high volcanic cone in the Auckland 
		volcanic field in Auckland, New Zealand.
		Located in the Remuera suburb, to the east of the Newmarket commercial suburb, it has been extensively modified 
		by human use, first by Māori for use as a pā and later by use as quarry and pasture land before finally having a 
		water reservoir installed in its cone to supply the surrounding area. An additional, partially buried, water 
		reservoir was built on the low southern side of the mountain in 1955. English oaks and pōhutukawa are the most 
		common trees on the hill.</description>
        <picture>mt_hobson</picture>
        <latitude>-36.86667</latitude>
        <longitude>174.78333</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>
	
	<place>
        <id>34</id>
        <name>Maungauika</name>
        <category>6</category>
        <description>Maungauika is a volcano forming a headland called North Head at the east end of the Waitemata 
		Harbour in Auckland, New Zealand in the suburb of Devonport. Known for its sweeping views over the harbour 
		and the Hauraki Gulf, since 1885 the head was mainly used by the military as a coastal defence installation, 
		which left a network of accessible old bunkers and tunnels as its legacy, forming part of the attraction. 
		The site was protected as part of Hauraki Gulf Maritime Park in 1972 and listed as a Category I historic 
		place in 2001. As part of a 2014 Treaty of Waitangi claim settlement the volcanic cone was officially 
		named Maungauika and the reserve renamed Maungauika / North Head Historic Reserve. Maungauika is the 
		Māori word for Mountain of Uika.</description>
        <picture>maungauika</picture>
        <latitude>-36.82708</latitude>
        <longitude>174.81182</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>
	
	<place>
        <id>35</id>
        <name>Mount Victoria</name>
        <category>6</category>
        <description>akarunga / Mount Victoria is the highest volcano on Auckland's North Shore, rising to 87 m. 
		Its age is currently unknown. Its lava flows now line much of Devonport's waterfront. An important pa once 
		occupied its slopes, and some of the pa's earthworks can still be seen. A scoria mound known as Duders 
		Hill, on Takarunga / Mount Victoria's southern slopes was mostly quarried away. The name Mount Victoria comes 
		from Queen Victoria and the name Takarunga means "the hill standing above". Jules Dumont d'Urville climbed 
		the hill in 1827.</description>
        <picture>mount_victoria</picture>
        <latitude>-36.82649</latitude>
        <longitude>174.79876</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>
	
	<place>
        <id>36</id>
        <name>Piha</name>
        <category>2</category>
        <description>A popular holiday resort with a lovely black-sand surf beach. Currents can be dangerous and swimmers 
		should stay between the flags during summer. North of the beach, walking trails lead to lookouts over the Tasman 
		Sea on Te Waha Point and Fisherman's Rock Point. For those with a head for heights, a steep track leads up Lion 
		Rock (101 metres), providing excellent views at the top. South of the beach, another track leads over the hill 
		to the Gap with its raging seas, and on to the Piha blowhole further up the valley.</description>
        <picture>piha</picture>
        <latitude>-36.95302</latitude>
        <longitude>174.46881</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>
	
	<place>
        <id>37</id>
        <name>Karekare</name>
        <category>2</category>
        <description>A beautiful surf beach hemmed in by high promontories at either end, with good walking tracks along 
		the cliff-tops overlooking the Tasman Sea.  A track leads around the shoreline to Whatipu but is only negotiable 
		at low tide. The opening scenes of Jane Campion's film The Piano were shot here.</description>
        <picture>karekare</picture>
        <latitude>-36.99376</latitude>
        <longitude>174.47001</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>
	
	<place>
        <id>38</id>
        <name>Whatipu</name>
        <category>2</category>
        <description>One of Auckland's scenic gems, this 12-kilometre-long black-sand beach is popular with surfers, 
		walkers and fishers. There are caves to explore along the length of the beach, and the sands now cover an old 
		kauri dance-floor which once hosted outdoor dances. Whatipu Lodge, a 140-year-old farmhouse behind the beach, 
		provides self-catering accommodation and a 1-hectare campsite with pit toilets and running water.</description>
        <picture>whatipu</picture>
        <latitude>-37.02799</latitude>
        <longitude>174.49539</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>
	
	<place>
        <id>39</id>
        <name>Muriwai</name>
        <category>2</category>
        <description>The longest of Auckland's west coast beaches (50 kilometres), Muriwai is part of an 183-hectare 
		regional park catering for swimmers, surfers, golfers, birdwatchers and bushwalkers. The beach is home to a 
		thriving gannet colony and a scenic boardwalk leads from the parking area to special viewing platforms, 
		allowing superb views of the birds. The cliffs behind Maori Bay, just around the south headland from Muriwai, 
		contain some of the world's best-preserved examples of pillow lava, formed by underwater volcanic eruptions 
		about 17 million years ago. Trails lead up into the bush from Waitea Road and provide good views up the coast. 
		Muriwai Beach Motor Camp, behind the sand dunes, offers caravan and tent sites, with hot showers, toilets, 
		laundry and cooking facilities.</description>
        <picture>muriwai</picture>
        <latitude>-36.82797</latitude>
        <longitude>174.42617</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>
	
	<place>
        <id>40</id>
        <name>Bethells</name>
        <category>2</category>
        <description>Named for the canoe-hull forms of the sand dunes, Te Henga was the location for many 
		scenes in the Hercules and Xena: Warrior Princess television series. The black sand stretches 
		for kilometres, while the rocks provide a good spot for fishing.</description>
        <picture>bethells</picture>
        <latitude>-36.89365</latitude>
        <longitude>174.44632</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>
	
	<place>
        <id>41</id>
        <name>Browns Bay</name>
        <category>2</category>
        <description>A great summer beach with it's occasionally clear waters and extensive long green area 
		not too far from the sand. There are several access points to Browns Bay with a side street road for 
		parking as well as along the main strip just behind the cafes, restaurants and several 
		ice cream/gelato stores in the town centre. 
		In classic East-coast style, you can see Rangitoto Island from the green or the golden sand. 
		It's already a fairly long beach but at low tide especially it becomes expansively so much sand. 
		At very high tide though there's almost none. The water itself is great for swimming and very popular as a result.</description>
        <picture>browns_bay</picture>
        <latitude>-36.71443</latitude>
        <longitude>174.74977</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>
	
	<place>
        <id>42</id>
        <name>Kohimarama</name>
        <category>2</category>
        <description>The next beach along from teeming Mission Bay, Kohi provides a welcome departure from the 
		throngs of crowds, and a bit of peace and quiet.
		Granted, there aren't nearly as many shops and cafes around (Kohi beach cafe/the Store are really the only 
		beachfront options), but as long as there's nice coffee and/or ice cream available.</description>
        <picture>kohimarama</picture>
        <latitude>-36.85020</latitude>
        <longitude>174.84468</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>
	
	<place>
        <id>43</id>
        <name>Milford Beach</name>
        <category>2</category>
        <description>Milford Beach in Auckland East Coast is a sheltered beach and reef break that only works once in a while. 
		Spring and Summer provide the best conditions. The best wind direction is from the west. Tends to receive distant 
		groundswells and the ideal swell angle is from the northeast. The beach break provides left and right handers and 
		there are also left and right hand reef breaks on offer.. Best around high tide. When the surf is up, it can get 
		quite busy in the water. Beware of rocks, locals and pollution.</description>
        <picture>milford</picture>
        <latitude>-36.76889</latitude>
        <longitude>174.77167</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>
	
	<place>
        <id>44</id>
        <name>Judges Bay</name>
        <category>2</category>
        <description>Judges Bay is located at the bottom of the Parnell Rose Gardens. Named after 3 magistrates who 
		built houses there in early colonial days, it became a tidal lagoon in the 1920s following the construction 
		of Tamaki Drive.
		Having undergone a major replenishment project in 2011, the bay is a popular swimming spot featuring a small 
		beach, jetty, pontoons and picnic tables. There is a also 1.6km walk covering the surrounding land taking you 
		through the rose gardens past St Stephens chapel and up to Point Resolution.</description>
        <picture>judges</picture>
        <latitude>-36.84909</latitude>
        <longitude>174.78761</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>
	
	<place>
        <id>45</id>
        <name>Mairangi Bay</name>
        <category>2</category>
        <description>This golden sand beach is wonderful as it's just behind the strip of many great little cafes 
		and shops as well as one of the beaches along East Coast bays with the concrete walkway. It's connected to 
		Murrays one way and Campbell's the other way and makes for a nice treat, especially with a buddy or a 4-legged companion. 
		It's best at low tide but it was also a shrieking-good surprise with the waves coming in at high tide as well.</description>
        <picture>mairangi</picture>
        <latitude>-36.73807</latitude>
        <longitude>174.75593</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>
	
	<place>
        <id>46</id>
        <name>M J Savage Memorial Park</name>
        <category>5</category>
        <description>Situated off Tamaki Drive near Mission Bay, The Michael Joseph Savage Memorial Park is set amongst 49 
		hectares of land with impressive panoramic views overlooking Waitemata harbour and Rangitoto Island.
		The tall obelisk, sunken pool and landscaped gardens is a memorial to New Zealand's first Labour Prime 
		Minister (1872 - 1940) and also the founder of the Welfare State.
		In 1860, 1879 and 1880 Ngati Whatua leaders Tuhaere and Te Kawau assembled many North Island chiefs to the 
		Kohimaramara Conference to establish a Maori Parliament. They sought to redress on land issues and equality 
		under the law. In the 1930's the Maori sought remedy through Michael Savage, the serving Prime Minister of 
		the Labour Government. With Maori support Labour had entered Parliament for the first time, beginning a long-standing relationship.</description>
        <picture>memorialpark</picture>
        <latitude>-36.84856</latitude>
        <longitude>174.82675</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>
	
	<place>
        <id>47</id>
        <name>Victoria Park</name>
        <category>5</category>
        <description>Victoria Park is a park and sports ground in Auckland City, New Zealand, it was opened in 
		1905 and named after the late Queen who had died four years earlier. It lies on reclaimed bay land in 
		Freemans Bay, a suburb directly west of the Auckland CBD. However, it does not have direct connection 
		to the foreshore anymore, as the Western Reclamation and the Viaduct Basin quarter lie between it and 
		the Waitemata Harbour. The bay started to be filled in as early as the 1870s although the bulk of the 
		reclamation appears to have happened after 1901. The Park was 'finished' around 1912, the area to the 
		north (called the Western Reclamation) dates from after that.</description>
        <picture>victoriapark</picture>
        <latitude>-36.84739</latitude>
        <longitude>174.75435</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>
	
	<place>
        <id>48</id>
        <name>Meola Reef Reserve</name>
        <category>5</category>
        <description>Meola Reef Reserve is a very large nature reserve of geological interest covers nearly 15 hectares.
		The longest lava flow in the Auckland volcanic field, it contains natural mangroves and salt marsh on the landward end.
		As a unique reef habitat for intertidal organisms in the Waitemata Harbour, it's a fascinating walk for those discoverers amongst us.</description>
        <picture>meola</picture>
        <latitude>-36.85763</latitude>
        <longitude>174.71139</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>
	
	<place>
        <id>49</id>
        <name>Auckland Regional Botanic Gardens</name>
        <category>5</category>
        <description>Auckland Botanic Gardens, Auckland, New Zealand is a botanical garden that covers 64 hectares
		in Manurewa, South Auckland. The first purchase of land by the Auckland Regional Authority (ARA) – predecessor 
		of Auckland Regional Council (ARC) – dates back to 1968. Developments started in 1973. The garden was officially 
		opened to the public in 1982. In that same year the first (and until now only) Visitors Guide was published.
		It now holds more than 10,000 plants.</description>
        <picture>botanic</picture>
        <latitude>-37.01142</latitude>
        <longitude>174.90719</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>
	
	<place>
        <id>50</id>
        <name>Ambury Regional Park</name>
        <category>5</category>
        <description>Ambury is a working farm, education centre and bird watcher’s paradise located on the shores of the Manukau Harbour.
​​		Beautiful scenery and fascinating history combine at Ambury – the park sits atop ash-covered lava flows and stone mounds 
		mark early Māori gardening sites.</description>
        <picture>ambury</picture>
        <latitude>-36.94581</latitude>
        <longitude>174.75926</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>
	
	<place>
        <id>51</id>
        <name>Waitakere Ranges Regional Parkland</name>
        <category>5</category>
        <description>The Waitakere Ranges are a chain of hills in the Auckland Region, generally running approximately 
		25 km (15.5 mi) from north to south, 25 km west of central Auckland, New Zealand. The maximum elevation within 
		the ranges is 474 m (1555 ft). The ranges and surrounding areas were traditionally known to local Māori as 
		Te Wao Nui o Tiriwa (The Great Forest of Tiriwa). It is under the jurisdiction of the Auckland Council.</description>
        <picture>waitakere</picture>
        <latitude>-36.95304	</latitude>
        <longitude>174.55902</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>
	
	<place>
        <id>52</id>
        <name>Kauri Point Centennial Park</name>
        <category>5</category>
        <description>Kauri Point Centennial Park is accessible off Onetaunga Road, and has walks that 
		take you to the tranquil beach of Kendall Bay. Several lookouts afford good views of the harbour. 
		Here is the only remaining example of a fortified pa on Waitemata Harbour. Some of the land 
		was originally owned by Sir John Logan Campbell. Much of the land was taken for harbour and 
		defence purposes earlier this century. In 1987, 22 hectares were purchased from the Harbour 
		Board to form the present park. Wetlands and regenerating native bush are a feature.</description>
        <picture>kauri</picture>
        <latitude>-36.82252</latitude>
        <longitude>174.70873</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>

	<place>
        <id>53</id>
        <name>Wenderholm</name>
        <category>5</category>
        <description>Wenderholm Regional Park is the first regional park of the Auckland Region, New Zealand.
		Situated between the estuaries of the Puhoi River and the Waiwera River, on the east coast of New Zealand's
		North Island, the park features a homestead known as Couldrey House, and a carved pouwhenua.
		This park also features a Maungatauhoro Te Hikoi walk, starting at the carved pouwhenua near the Couldrey
		House, and allows the park visitors to see scenic views and birdlife.
		The park has its own resident artist, and part is sectioned off for ecological restoration.</description>
        <picture>wenderholm</picture>
        <latitude>-36.53710</latitude>
        <longitude>174.71184</longitude>
        <note></note>
        <favorite>0</favorite>
    </place>
</resources>